Welcome to this comprehensive tutorial on video editing.
Today we'll learn about keyframe generation for mobile platforms.
This technique works perfectly on TikTok, Instagram Reels, and YouTube Shorts.
First, let's understand what keyframes actually are.
Keyframes mark important transition points in your video timeline.
They help maintain viewer attention and improve retention rates.
Now, let's look at the scene-based approach.
Each scene should be between 10 and 20 seconds for optimal engagement.
This prevents viewer fatigue while maintaining narrative flow.
Next, we need to select appropriate transitions between scenes.
Crossfades work well for related content with smooth flow.
Use dip to black for major topic changes or dramatic shifts.
The third step is optimizing for mobile-first consumption.
Always render in 9:16 vertical format at 1080 by 1920 pixels.
This ensures perfect display on mobile devices.
However, you might need to adapt content for different platforms.
YouTube prefers 16:9 landscape which can be letterboxed from vertical.
Facebook and Instagram also support square 1:1 format.
Finally, let's talk about encoding specifications.
Use H.264 codec with yuv420p pixel format for universal compatibility.
Set frame rate to 30 fps and GOP size to 60 frames.
The fifth important point is transition timing.
Keep transitions between 0.3 and 0.7 seconds for best results.
Too fast feels jarring, too slow loses viewer attention.
Lastly, always test your videos on actual mobile devices.
What looks good on desktop might not work well on phones.
Check transitions, text readability, and overall flow.
Now you have all the tools to create engaging mobile videos.
Remember to focus on retention and viewer experience.
Start with your SRT subtitles and let the content guide the structure.
Thank you for watching this tutorial.
Subscribe for more tips on video production and editing.
See you in the next video!